<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Michael</firstname>
      <surname>Fink</surname>
    </author>
    <copyright>
      <year>2004</year>
      <holder>Michael Fink</holder>
    </copyright>
  </bookinfo>
  <title>Underworld Adventures Debugger Manual</title>

  <epigraph><attribution>Douglas N. Adams</attribution>
    <para>
      We are stuck with technology when what we really want is just stuff that
      works. How do you recognize something that is still technology? A good
      clue is if it comes with a manual.
    </para>
  </epigraph>

  <preface><title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
      This Manual describes the Underworld Adventures Debugger, an add-on piece
      of software for Underworld Adventures, the project that tries to recreate
      the old Ultima[tm] Underworld games on modern operating systems and
      platforms.
    </para>
    <para>
      The Underworld Adventures Debugger mainly exists to create custom games
      using the Underworld Adventures engine and one of the Underworld games as
      a "template". It helps creating maps, placing objects and critters,
      writing conversation scripts and debugging Lua scripts that further help
      to customize the game.
    </para>
    <para>
      The Manual describes the all features of the Debugger and what you can do
      with it. It also shows you how you create a new game with it. The
      conversation script language is described in detail.
    </para>
  </preface>

  <chapter><title>The debugger user interface</title>

    <section><title>The main debugger window</title>
    <para>
      The Debugger main window that appears after pressing the debug key (see
      the Underworld Adventures Manual) consists of several user interface items:
      The title bar, the menu, the toolbar, the work area and the status bar. The
      work area can contain windows that show game info and the like.
    </para>
    <para>
      There are two different type of windows: dockable windows and normal
      windows. Dockable windows can be docked at every side of the work area, as
      well as just "floating" in the work area. When the window is docked, it
      makes the work area smaller. Dockable windows cannot be resized to the
      whole screen (at least they were not designed as such). Normal windows can
      be resized in any direction and they can be minimized to an icon or
      maximized to the whole size of the work area.
    </para>
    </section>

    <section><title>Debugger concepts</title>
    <para>
      This section explains how the debugger works in relation to the main
      application, the Underworld Adventures engine.
    </para>

    <para>
    </para>
    </section>

    <section><title>Window types</title>
    <para>
      This section describes the various windows that can be shown in the work
      area of the debugger.
    </para>

    <section><title>Player Info</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </section>

    <section><title>Master Object List</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </section>

    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter><title>Creating a new custom game</title>
    <section><title>Creating a project</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>
