<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Michael</firstname>
      <surname>Fink</surname>
    </author>
    <copyright>
      <year>2004</year>
      <holder>Michael Fink</holder>
    </copyright>
  </bookinfo>
  <title>Underworld Adventures Manual</title>

  <preface><title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
    Welcome to the Underworld Adventures Manual. This manual explains all
    things that have to do with configuring and running Underworld Adventures.
    Please note that this is not the manual for Ultima Underworld I or II.
    </para>

    <para>
    To play the games using Underworld Adventures, you definitely need the
    original game om floppy discs or on CD-ROM (when using the "Electronic
    Arts Presents CD-Rom Classics : Ultima Underworld I &amp; II" CD). It would
    also be good to have the original manuals.
    </para>

    <section><title>System Requirements</title>
    <para>
    Here is a list of things you should have to fully (or at all) relive
    the old games in new clothes:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>A modern 32-bit processor (600 MHz or above recommended)</listitem>
      <listitem>A modern Operating System (Windows, Linux, etc.)</listitem>
      <listitem>A decent 3D-Graphics card with current OpenGL drivers, e.g. an Nvidia GeForce</listitem>
      <listitem>A Sound card</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </section>
  </preface>

  <chapter><title>Configuration Guide</title>
    <para>
    This chapter describes how to set up and configure Underworld Adventures
    to run the old Ultima Underworld games.
    </para>

    <section><title>Installing the old games</title>
    This section has yet to be written.
    </section>

    <section><title>Command line options</title>
    This section has yet to be written.
    </section>

    <section><title>Configuration file</title>
    This section has yet to be written.
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter><title>Running Underworld Adventures</title>
    <para>
    Underworld Adventures is played just like Ultima Underworld I and II.
    However there are some minor things that are not in the old games.
    </para>

    <!-- section><title>Underworld Adventures Menu</title>
    This section has yet to be written.
    </section -->

    <section><title>Savegames</title>
    <section><title>Load/Save screen</title>
    <para>
    One limitation of the Underworld games were the number of savegames one
    can use during the game. Underworld Adventures lifts that limitation by
    providing practically unlimited number of savegames. Another way had to be
    found in Underworld Adventures to access and handle those.
    </para>

    <para>
    Underworld Adventures introduces the savegame Load/Save screen that is
    used to either load a savegame, e.g. when using "Journey Onward" on the
    game's screen, or when selecting "Save Game" or "Restore Game" in the
    game's builtin menu. The old way of accessing the savegames via buttons
    numbered I to IV and savegame descriptions listed in the text scroll are
    gone now.
    </para>
    </section>
    <section><title>Quicksave Feature</title>
    <para>
    The current game can quickly be saved using the Quicksave feature. The
    key F11 saves the current game to a special Quicksave slot. With F12 one
    can restore the previously saved quicksave savegame. If you have modified
    the key bindings, look up the keys used for quickloading and quicksaving
    in the modified keymap.cfg.
    </para>
    </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter><title>Operating System Specific Documentation</title>
    <para>
    This chapter contains operating system specific documentation about
    Underworld Adventures.
    </para>

    <section><title>Windows 9x, ME, 2000 and XP</title>
    This section has yet to be written.
    </section>

    <section><title>Linux, FreeBSD and other Unices</title>
    <para>
    Please read the following excerpt from the SDL_mixer home page if you use
    timidity under Linux:
    </para>
    <para>
    SDL_Mixer supports playing MIDI format files using software wavetable via
    an old version of timidity. This requires you to have a GUS compatible set
    of sound patches on your system. By default, the library looks for these
    patches on Win32 in C:\timidity, and on UNIX in /usr/local/lib/timidity/.
    The patches are available here: 
    <ulink url="http://www.libsdl.org/projects/SDL_mixer/timidity/timidity.tar.gz"/>
    </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter><title>Miscellaneous Information</title>
    <section><title>Differences to the original game</title>
    <para>
    While creating Underworld Adventures there were some things that were
    done differently than in the original games. Reasons for this are mainly
    to simplify the game, to improve it in some way, or just to implement
    things in another way that else would have been too difficult or hard to
    do.
    </para>

    <para>
    Here is the list of things that are different than in Ultima Underworld 1.
    Some of the options can be switched off with the "enable-uwadv-features"
    setting in the configure file. See Section x for that.
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        Up/down view angle can be varied between -75 and 75 degree, as opposed
        to something like 45 degrees in the original (can be switched off).
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       Cutscene speech is played a bit too slow (due to some technical reasons
       the audio samples isn't exactly converted to the proper frequency).
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       The input cursor in text scrolls (e.g. in conversations) is a vertical
       line, and not a blinking cursor square. The cursor can be moved to any
       position in the input field.
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </section>

    <section><title>Contributors</title>
    <para>
    This section lists all contributors that contributed to the making of
    Underworld Adventures in some or other way.
    </para>
    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Michael Fink (vividos)</listitem>
      <listitem>Willem Jan Palenstijn (wjp)</listitem>
      <listitem>Dirk Manders (phlask)</listitem>
      <listitem>Jim Cameron (hairyjim)</listitem>
      <listitem>Kasper Fauerby (Telemachos)</listitem>
      <listitem>Martin Gircys-Shetty (QQtis)</listitem>
      <listitem>Ryan Nunn (Colourless Dragon)</listitem>
      <listitem>Tels</listitem>
      <listitem>Cuneyt Cuneyitoglu</listitem>
      <listitem>Radoslaw Grzanka</listitem>
      <listitem>Sam Matthews (servus)</listitem>
      <listitem>Marc A. Pelletier (Coren)</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

</book>
